( Flutter of wings )
( Sniffs )
( Exhales )
( Guard 's whistle )
Come on , sir , give us a penny !
Run !
Sorry .
Lucky heather , sir ? Come on , sir .
Looking for someone ?
Er ... Yes , actually , I ...
Mr. Gray . Welcome to London , sir .
DRIVER : Go on , lady . Off you go !
Whoa .
And here we are , sir . Welcome home .
I hope you 'll find everything to your liking , sir .
Nothing 's changed since I was a boy .
Sir .
I 'm sorry for your loss , sir .
May I prepare some tea ?
Thank you , Victor .
( Creaking )
( Melancholy melody )
I 've no doubt London will hold many new friends and adventures for you .
- I hope so . - So do I.
Oh ! This is somebody you simply must meet .
This is one of our finest artists , Basil Hallward .
Agatha , please , a humble student of beauty .
- What do you think ? - Oh .
AGATHA : That 's quite a likeness .
- Basil . - Hmm ?
I 've been in London two weeks now .
The only people I 've met are Agatha 's charitable group .
Well , you 've met me .
Of course .
I didn 't mean ...
These parties are terribly dull , Dorian .
- You won 't be missing anything . - I 'm sure you 're right .
I just ...
.. thought it might be fun .
( String quartet plays )
MAN : Oh ...
Dear me , no .
Shabby .
Wife , drink .
There . I 'll fetch us some drinks .
WOMAN : Find her a good husband who knows how to behave to a woman .
The only way to behave is to make love to her if she 's pretty
and to someone else if she 's plain . Excuse me .
( Laughter )
Cigarette ?
No , thank you .
I find a cigarette to be the perfect pleasure .
It is exquisite
and leaves one unsatisfied .
( Women laugh )
You 're Kelso 's grandson .
Yes .
- Did you know him ? - I met him once .
It was enough to give a cheer last month
when he rasped his last sour breath .
One assumes you inherited the withered old goat 's estate ?
Being a little orphan isn 't all bad .
" An earnest young man with a beautiful nature , " according to Agatha .
I 'd pictured some freckled country oaf in ghastly dress .
I see I was only half right .
It could be worse .
Gladys Allonby 's been dressed for her 14th birthday ever since her 40th .
If Radley spent less time in church and more at his tailor 's ,
he might not so resemble a badly-bound hymn book .
Are you sure you won 't take a cigarette ?
I get them directly from Cairo .
I see you 've met our charming host .
Hm ?
Pay no attention to anything he tells you .
How rude . Henry Wotton .
Victoria , my wife .
My aunt , alas , you know .
Oh , I 'm so glad you 've met . You might learn some manners from this boy .
I 've found some more guests for you to insult .
I knew I kept her for something .
I do hope our paths cross again , Mr. Gray .
Thank you for the cigarette ... ( Coughs ) .. cigarette .
An acquired taste .
- No , it 's actually quite pleasant . - No , I meant Henry .
( Giggles )
There 's some people I want you to meet .
( Gas lamp sputters )
( Rumble of thunder )
( Sputtering continues )
( Gas lamp sputters )
MAN : Dorian ... - ( Bolt clanks back )
( Whimpers )
( Rats squeak and scamper )
( Fluttering )
( Rats scampering )
( Rats squeak )
( Clink )
DORIAN : Aren 't you tired of looking at me yet ?
BASIL : Certainly not .
The more I look ...
.. the more I see .
It must be nearly finished , man . It isn 't the Sistine Chapel .
Do you remember when I told you you could sit in if you were quiet ?
- I want to see it . - No , no , don 't .
He won 't even let me have a peek .
Agatha tells me your father was also an artist .
- Apparently so . - Kelso must have been delighted ,
his daughter falling for some penniless painter .
( Laughs )
No wonder they eloped .
- I never knew my parents . - Of course .
Typhus is so awful .
Your poor mother carried off in childbirth .
Do you take such interest in everyone you meet ?
Not everyone I meet is so interesting .
Henry , why don 't you go for a stroll ,
while I just work up the background ?
You don 't need Dorian for that .
Let 's both take a break .
- Perhaps we should all get some air . - Yes , and I know just the place .
MAN : Look . It 's rancid ! It 's rancid ! It 's only five days old . I 'm not paying .
( Shouting and screaming )
Come on , Dorian .
Sorry .
You see why Agatha is so keen to help Whitechapel ?
Don 't you think we should at least try to make a difference ?
I 've no desire to change anything in England , except the weather .
( Fiddle music )
Welcome to my little Hellfire Club .
- Here you are , gents . - In one .
No , don 't , don 't .
- ( Coughs ) - Barkeeper .
Again .
How say you and the handsome young man stuff me double ?
Er , no , thank you . We nonetheless wish you godspeed
on your evening 's quest for romance .
MAN : A little wider , my dear .
Oh ! ( Giggles )
Don 't worry . He 's a doctor .
There 's no shame in pleasure , Mr. Gray .
Man just wants to be happy .
But society wants him to be good . And when he 's good , Man is rarely happy .
But when he 's happy , he 's always good .
You do want to be good , don 't you , Mr. Gray , and happy ?
Isn 't there a price to pay for that sort of business ?
She 's quite affordable .
But what I was asking was about the effect on ...
Buy a lady a drink ?
- On what ? - Well , on one 's soul .
One 's soul ?
This is my church .
With this dram , right now , I nail my soul to the Devil 's altar .
You 'll never meet a more eloquent philosopher of pure folly .
Come on , Dorian . It 's time we showed you what we 've made .
- Really ? - The boy hasn 't finished his gin .
Go and fiddle with your background . We 'll be along shortly .
( Drunken singing )
BASIL : Your picture awaits you , Dorian .
Perhaps you should go and speak to her .
I didn 't realize she ...
Don 't be timid . Go .
- I wouldn 't know where to ... - You see , I envy you .
Me ?
Everything 's possible for you
because you have the only two things worth having .
Youth ...
and beauty .
Come on , let 's go .
The moment 's lost .
That was probably her husband .
Yes , very sensible .
People die of common sense , Dorian ,
one lost moment at a time .
Life is a moment . There is no hereafter .
So make it burn always
with the hardest flame .
HENRY : Well , Basil ...
.. it 's quite the best thing you 've done .
You 'll be the talk of the town .
Both of you .
Speak up , boy . You 'll hurt his feelings .
Is that really how I look ?
It 's just so ...
.. life-like .
HENRY : Better than life .
He 'll always look like that .
You , Mr. Gray , I 'm afraid will not .
In time , Mother Nature will come a very poor second to Father Basil .
- Some things are precious for not lasting . - Poppycock .
We wither and scar because the gods are cruel and hateful .
Perhaps I should nail my soul to the Devil 's altar .
And remain as you are ? Fair trade .
How about another gin instead ?
All that hocus-pocus , endless conjurations ,
books bound in infant skin ,
pentacles of fire , drinking the blood of virgins .
Dorian wouldn 't really barter his soul .
Would you , Dorian ?
Would you ?
Yes .
( Gasps and applause )
Oh , you really have captured something quite exquisite , Basil .
I 've never known a subject so unaffected .
The brush just seemed to dance and I just painted what I saw .
Kelso will turn in his grave .
He didn 't care to look at me .
He blamed me for my mother ,
for her death .
There are no limits to the ugliness of old men .
Lips ! And his eyes !
Almost a match for the original .
- You must get used to being looked at . - Well , it 's a fine painting .
- I don 't mean the painting . - Mr. Gray , if you please .
- That went rather well , didn 't it ? - A triumph , Mr. Gray .
The first of many .
May I say , sir ,
your mother would be very proud to see you today .
Shall I draw your bath ?
It 's rather early .
Do we have any gin ?
I believe not , sir .
Then perhaps you might summon me a hansom ?
- Go on , poke him ! - I am poking him !
Check his pockets !
Oi !
Yes ?
- Wet your pizzle , sir ? - Hello , handsome .
( Barks )
( Woman laughs )
( Man laughs drunkenly ) Boy !
( Ship 's bell and cry of seagulls )
Have a box , my lord ? Just a bob .
You 've only missed a little .
This young lady ...
Miss Sibyl Vane , my lord , in the role of Ophelia .
.. see that noble and most sovereign reason
like sweet bells jangled , out of tune and harsh .
That unmatch 'd form and feature of blown youth
blasted with ecstasy .
Oh , woe is me .
( Door opens )
MANAGER : May I present
the Theatre Royale 's Miss Sibyl Vane , my lord ?
( Door closes )
I 'm not really a lord .
I don 't know why he keeps saying that .
We don 't get many gentlemen in this theatre .
Really ?
Well , then , I shall recommend it ...
.. to them .
( Clears throat )
May I ask what brings you to my dressing room ?
Well , I ...
I just happened to be passing the theatre and ...
- Well , you see , I was in the gin shop ... - I know .
You remember ?
Well , a friend took me there for the first time .
Well , I say the first time . Of course , I have ...
Well , I wanted to ... wanted to say hello ,
but then you left with ...
- With Jim . - Yes .
Quite .
Jim .
My brother .
Brother ?
- Mm . - Well , that 's splendid !
Sorry . It was wrong of me to ...
Please forgive my intrusion , Miss Vane .
Wait ! There 's something you haven 't told me .
Yes , of course .
I do beg your pardon .
Ophelia is a most challenging role
and your performance this evening was ... impeccable .
In fact , extraordinary .
In fact ...
.. you are extraordinary .
And when I saw you on the stage ,
and even more so , now I stand before you ,
I am awestruck and humbled by your radiance .
I meant your name .
You didn 't tell me your name .
( Both laugh )
So , how many other girls do you bring here ?
Hundreds .
Thousands .
- You must be courting dozens at least . - No .
You can tell me the truth .
There 's only you .
Tell me , what are your actual relations with this young thing ?
- A fraction of respect , man . - It 's not like that . Sibyl 's sacred .
It 's only the scared things that are worth touching .
People nowadays fear their passions .
- Well , I don 't . - Of course you do .
We 're taught terror from the nursery .
Terror of God ,
or , even worse , of scandal .
We 're taught to spend our entire lives cowering in self-denial .
The truth , Mr. Gray , is that every impulse we strangle only poisons us .
You 'll make him wish he 'd never mentioned the girl .
Voilà , monsieur .
There 's something missing .
Thank you , Harry .
I took the liberty of filling it with my blend .
Oh , Dorian .
- ( Dorian plays piano ) - It 's beautiful .
I just thought it would suit you .
I should be going . Jim will worry .
Of course .
Or we could ...
I mean ...
You could ...
.. stay ...
.. here ...
.. with me .
We shouldn 't be afraid of our feelings , Sib .
It 's just ...
I 've seen other girls
who give themselves , and then I 've seen what becomes of them .
I love you .
Forgive me . I didn 't mean ...
You 're all I ever want in the world .
( Lock clunks )
Boy !
You might have a little scar there .
Well , it won 't be a first .
My back .
What ?
You 're perfect .
- Engaged ? - It 's wonderful , isn 't it ?
( Ladies murmur )
I wanted you all to be the first to know .
- Congratulations , Dorian . - Thank you .
May I ask how you came to propose marriage ?
I suppose I didn 't really make a formal proposal .
I told her I loved her . She said it was her dream come true to be my wife .
Women are wonderfully practical .
( Laughter )
Will you all come and see her perform tonight ?
I 'm afraid I have an engagement .
( Clears throat )
And we 're due at the Burdons .
Tell Burdon I 'll see him tomorrow . Why don 't you hail us a hansom ?
- I love acting . - Goodbye , ladies .
So much more real than life .
I hope you 're pleased with yourself .
Every experience is of value .
And marriage is certainly an experience .
Nobody is amused this time , Henry .
I 'll talk to him .
DORIAN : I got the sense the others don 't quite approve . Especially Basil .
Perhaps Basil should be a little more fearless with his own feelings .
I thought we might make a little stop en route to the theatre .
I too have news .
It seems my wife is with child .
Oh , congratulations .
Don 't be absurd . It 's the beginning of the end .
So , indulge me .
- Ah , Harry . - Alan .
Firkytoodling at last , I see .
- Come along , ladies . - It 's good to see you .
How delightful .
Hello .
Drink up .
It won 't be long before you 're anchored to the perambulator .
I don 't think so .
Our friend is to marry .
Ah , but we haven 't had a chance to win your heart .
HENRY : Oh , well .
Farewell to youth .
No .
Watch your step .
Does Victoria know you come here ?
My dear boy , marriage makes a life of deception absolutely necessary .
Well , perhaps I have a stronger conscience .
Conscience is just a polite term for cowardice .
No civilized man regrets a pleasure .
You see ?
The only way to get rid of a temptation is to yield to it .
Be searching always for new sensations , Dorian .
Come .
Come upstairs .
Forbid yourself nothing .
Come .
- Nobody at all need know . - Come with me .
( Moans of ecstasy )
HENRY : The pleasure is all mine .
- I 've heard so much about you . - And I you .
Did you enjoy the show ? I couldn 't see you in the audience .
I 'm afraid we ran a little late .
Oh , where were you ?
At the club .
The truth is , my dear , we were celebrating your wonderful news .
Very many congratulations .
And Harry is to be a father .
How wonderful .
- Indeed . - In one .
I 'm sure you 're eager to start a family , too ?
Very much .
( Laughs )
Well , not quite yet .
- Good night . - Good night , Charlie .
'Night .
We 're a little young , don 't you think ?
Are we ?
Perhaps I should take my leave .
- Good night . - Er ...
See you tomorrow , Harry .
I 'm sure .
I don 't think we need to rush , that 's all .
( Beats drum )
You sound different .
Not at all .
Were you at the club all night ?
Yes .
He 's a better liar than you .
What ?
I was just saying everything is so soon .
- I gave myself to you . I thought you loved me . - And I do !
Then make me your wife , not one of your whores !
I think perhaps I ought to go .
Don 't let him do this , Dorian .
- This has nothing to do with Harry . - You said you loved me !
And I do ! I do !
Dorian , please !
Please , Dorian ! Please , I love you !
( Door slams )
( Fly buzzes )
( Chatter and laughter )
Oh , Henry ! Dorian !
Tell me , how was last night 's performance ?
I 'm sorry .
Have a drink .
I can introduce you to the artist later , if you like .
Never marry , Mr. Gray .
It 's the only way to keep all one 's illusions .
Chin up , dear boy . You 've a face like a slapped nancy .
You 'll love again .
And again . Do you have your cigarettes ?
Of course .
Don 't fear it , Dorian .
The world is yours .
For a season .
( Whispering )
Hello , Victor . Could you fetch us a bottle of the ... ?
Anything !
- What 's the matter ? - You 've a visitor , sir .
A Mr. Vane . He seems disturbed .
We 'll wait in the library .
Victor , how about that bottle ?
( Laughter )
To what do I owe the pleasure , Jim ?
Can I er ... Can I get you something to drink ?
I don 't want this in my house .
What happened with Sibyl was very unfortunate .
But this was a gift
and she really should keep ...
It 's filthy .
She was wearing it when they pulled her from the river .
Why on earth was she ... ?
She ... she can 't ...
She can 't ...
I wanted you to know ... she loved you .
She was going to have your child .
And you killed her .
Jim ! Jim !
Get up !
Are you all right , sir ?
Let me ...
- help you up . - Sibyl 's dead .
- Now , now . - Good night , ladies .
( Jim sobs and shouts )
Get up . Get up !
We can 't have maniacs threatening decent people in their own homes .
Alan treats a number of such deranged cases at Broadmoor .
Just until he settles down .
I 'm confident any inquest into this unfortunate business
will find no connection whatsoever with Mr. Gray .
- ( Jim roars ) - Taking you downtown .
( Jim screams )
( Door closes )
This wasn 't your fault , Dorian .
- Kelso said I was death . - Well , he was wrong .
Salome .
Harry ?
You 're not making sense .
No ! Please !
( Scream )
He 's part of me , Harry .
- I turn all love into death . - Dorian . Dorian !
Into death . Death !
Kelso was a bitter ruin of a man and he 's dead .
What 's past is past .
Experience makes us strong , Dorian .
And you need to see this episode for what it really is .
An extraordinary experience .
- I can 't be so heartless . - It isn 't heartless .
It 's finding a perspective .
Most lack the strength to rise above life 's suffering .
To rule one 's emotions ,
to savor them ...
.. that takes a man of will .
Alan left this for you .
Drink . Doctor 's orders .
I should be going .
I 'll call in the morning .
Thank you , Harry .
You are a man of will , Dorian .
I knew it from the first .
( Squelching )
Dorian , Dorian ...
I 'm so , so sorry .
Harry ... Harry told me about poor Sibyl .
If there 's anything I can do ...
You 're very kind . I 'm actually just on my way to see Harry now .
- Are you coming to the Radleys ' ball ? - Er ...
Where 's my picture ?
The light was too strong in here .
The light was perfect . Where have you put it ?
It 's quite safe .
The truth is , I don 't want it on public show .
It 's just too valuable .
I could forgive the vagaries of grief if you actually seemed to be grieving .
I was ...
stricken .
But what 's past is past .
Every experience is of value . Drink ?
You shouldn 't believe every word Harry says .
He doesn 't .
Isn 't this all just ghastly ? Radley gloating with pitiful pride
while his love-starved wife
parades her daughter like a sow truffling for husbands .
RADLEY : Delightful little filly .
And poor Celia .
Trussed up in a doily for some chinless miscreant to eternally enslave .
I suggest we raise a little hell .
Allow me to introduce myself .
I know who you are , Mr. Gray .
Allow me to offer my congratulations on your ravishing debut .
Perhaps a small toast .
To what ?
Intoxication .
- Here she comes . - Who ?
- ( Mumbles ) - Celia ?
- Celia ? - Problem , Lady Radley ?
My daughter , I can 't find her .
And nor can I find your Mr. Gray .
Perhaps they 're in the garden . The arrangements are marvelous .
Ah .
Might I hazard an alternative suggestion ?
Waltz
( Hums waltz )
Celia !
- Is something the matter ? - Celia !
Where is my daughter , you beast ?
I was just attending to my costume .
A little of Lord Radley 's very fine Burgundy was spilt on my shirt cuff .
Oh . Oh ...
Mr. Gray , I ...
- Lord Henry gave me to understand ... - A mistake .
Nobody at all need know .
You 're too kind , Mr. Gray .
- Thank you . - It must be difficult ,
a party like this .
Seeing your daughter come of age .
Makes you long for your own youth .
I ...
Madam , forgive me but ...
.. you are exquisite .
Oh , Mr. Gray .
This is most improper . ( Gasps )
Ooh ...
Ah !
Oh !
Now , where were we ?
( Applause )
What are you grinning about , Gray ?
I think Harry 's just lost a wager .
Well , come on , out with it . We 're all gambling men here .
Just a little round of double or nothing .
( Laughs )
Of course , a good gambler understands that there are limits .
BOTH : There are no limits .
( Thunder )
( Operatic singing in Italian )
Have a wonderful birthday , Dorian !
( Laughs ) Dorian .
This crush is your finest yet .
One has to do something to null the pain of age .
Do tell my husband not to be so disagreeable .
But I always agree with him .
Congratulations , Basil . I hear you have a new exhibition .
Yes , yes , in Paris .
Yes , in fact , I wanted to ask a question of you , Dorian .
I 'd like to make your portrait my principal piece .
Oh , yes , that picture . Absolutely wonderful .
- Whatever became of it ? - I haven 't seen it myself in months .
- He 's very protective of it , aren 't you ? - Indeed I am .
I 'm very sorry , Basil , but it 's just too precious .
I won 't have it out of the house .
( Moans of pleasure )
I beg your pardon .
Did you want me ?
That picture is my finest work and it 'd be greatly appreciated ...
The greatest gift that anyone could ever have given .
In fact ...
In fact , I wish that I could tell you just how great .
But then it isn 't so unreasonable to borrow it back a little while .
I 'm not sure that I 've ever ...
.. fully expressed my gratitude .
I hardly think ...
( African drumbeat )
I have the key to your heart .
Don 't touch that ever !
Dorian !
He 's young .
But he was never cruel
till he met you .
That 's mine .
( Drumbeat intensifies )
( Knocking )
- ( Door opens ) DORIAN : Oh , it 's you .
- I thought you 'd gone home . - I just needed a walk .
I was just about to go to bed . Everyone 's left .
I 'm here to see you , not them .
Really ?
Wait , wait .
I don 't know where to begin .
How ominous .
- You terrified that poor boy tonight . - He seemed to recover .
Is that what you tell yourself about Celia Radley ?
Look , I 'm sorry about her misfortune .
But do you really believe that I 'm to blame ?
When I look at you , I find it impossible to imagine .
But I know you 're treating people poorly .
Even me ,
when I ask you the small favor that you loan me my own picture ...
- Is that what this is about ? - No , it 's about a good deal more !
Dorian ...
What happened to the Dorian Gray I painted ?
You just don 't understand .
I will always ...
be that Dorian .
Can I trust you , Basil ?
Would you like to see why you can never exhibit that picture ?
What 's the matter ?
Don 't you recognize me ?
What have you ... ?
That thing ...
It isn 't what ...
Together , we 've created something beautiful .
It 's a miracle .
Look at me .
Because of your painting ...
- It 's not ... - .. this will never age .
Will never scar .
Can you even imagine
being able to do anything you please ...
.. and live out every whim and impulse
while the world just sees you gleam ?
This isn 't you .
I know this isn 't you . We can stop it !
Basil , please , don 't .
Don 't you see that this must be destroyed ?
Dorian , I want to help you .
We 'll find a priest or a spirit-worker .
( Scrape of broken glass )
There 's good in your heart . I 've seen it .
You 're not this ...
this devil !
I 'm a god .
Basil .
Basil !
( Basil chokes )
( Basil moans gently )
( Flutter of wings )
( Echo of howling wind )
( Sniffs )
( Exhales )
( Gasps )
( Thunder )
Good evening .
Need some help , sir ?
How kind .
( Rattling thud )
All right .
Mind how you go , sir .
On you go .
( Ship 's horn )
( Clanking and grinding )
( Woman screams )
( Moans of ecstasy )
( Rasping gasp )
( Rasping sigh )
Good day , Lady Victoria .
I was about to take Harry for lunch at Scott 's . Why don 't you join us ?
Oh , Dorian . You haven 't heard .
They 've found Basil 's body in the river .
Thou art slave to Fate ,
Chance , kings and desperate men ,
And dost with poyson , warre and sicknesse dwell ,
And poppies or charmes can make us sleepe as well ,
And better than thy stroake .
Why swell 'st thou then ?
One short sleepe past ,
we wake eternally .
And death shall be no more .
Death , thou shalt die .
Farewell , dear Basil .
DORIAN : I spoke to the police again this morning .
And have the buffoons managed to make a single inch of progress ?
They 're convinced it was some Shadwell renter .
They think they 'll catch him .
So Basil 's name will be dragged through the gutter .
I 'm of a mind to take a trip , Harry .
Maybe you should join me .
- Where are you going ? - Everywhere .
I leave tomorrow .
With all this ?
Someone once gave me some fine advice ...
.. about taking perspective .
Come with me .
The child is imminent .
Tell me everything .
I always do .
DORIAN : I 've entered the tombs of dead nations ,
ridden with our last savage tribes .
I feel the brilliance of every moment ,
the splendor of existence and its awful ...
.. keen as the edge of a blade , this desperate will to see , touch and ...
Dearest Harry , you taught me that life must burn with a hard flame .
Its light does not blind me ,
nor its heat sear me .
I am the flame , Harry .
I am the flame .
( Rasping gasp )
( Gramophone crackles )
HENRY : Women never have anything to say , but they say it charmingly .
They 're the great triumph of matter over mind .
( Laughter )
Well , here I am .
Dorian .
You look so ...
.. so ...
( Whispering )
He looks magnificent .
We have heard such tales .
I 'm afraid they 're all absolutely and entirely ... true .
( Murmuring )
Welcome back .
Some champagne ?
Yes .
A-ha !
My missing guest of honor .
I 'm coming .
I was sorry for your loss .
You know , I kept hearing this phrase .
" Natural causes . "
Nature has a great deal to answer for .
She was so looking forward to the life of a divorcee .
And poor old Basil ...
If we paid the police by results , we 'd save the Treasury thousands .
When your letters stopped coming , I feared the worst .
But here you are .
So never mind the country estate .
Tell me , why are you really back ?
- I 'm tired . - You don 't look it .
You have no right to melancholy .
Your life is exquisite .
You 've drunk deeply of everything and it hasn 't left a fleck on you .
Do you remember when I first came to London ?
I felt so ...
Those were the great days .
Dorian , it 's quite clear why you 've lost your passion for life .
You 've been away from me for too long .
We must go out .
Take on the town , as we used to .
- I 've missed you , Harry . - I must ask you , though ...
What is your secret ?
If I told you , I 'd have to kill you .
You still have it , I see .
- From Cairo . - Where else ?
Smile .
Emily .
May I ?
I hope I 'm not interrupting your reminiscence ?
The one charm of the past is that it 's the past .
Oh . I hope you 're not also a dreary old cynic ?
What is there to believe in ?
Our developments .
All I see is decay .
Well , religion ?
Fashionable substitute for belief .
- Art ? - A malady .
- Love ? - An illusion .
Bravo !
Well , you both cut the world to pieces , don 't you ?
Thank you for the cigarette .
Unusual woman .
She ought to be . She 's my daughter .
( Screaming )
( Coughing and cries of pain )
Lie down .
( Man screams )
( Rasping gasp )
Dorian ?
Dorian ...
It 's you .
Dorian !
BOY : Oi , mister ! Give us a penny !
Oi , mister . Mister . Penny for the Guy ?
- Have you been in the war ? - I 'm too old .
Give us a couple of bob for a drink , will you ?
( Screaming )
( Cry of seagulls )
( Roll of thunder )
( Man coughs )
( Debris rattles underfoot )
Get up . Get up !
You ...
Yeah , you ... Dorian Gray .
- I think you 're mistaken . - I knew one day you 'd come back .
- Wait , please ... - So many years I 've waited .
Wait ! How many years ?
- No more ! - How many years ?
Look at me . Look at my face .
I 'm barely 20 , man .
Can 't be .
I don 't know this ...
this Dorian Gray .
I think , sir , you are not well .
I ...
Hospital .
They hurt me .
You tell him ...
You tell him I 'm coming .
( Squeaking )
( Rasping gasp )
( Creaking and squelching )
( Coughs )
VICTOR : A visitor , sir .
To what do I owe the pleasure ?
I thought you might like to join me for lunch .
No , I don 't think ...
I made a picnic .
Yes , well , I 'm afraid I ...
I 'd rather stay at home today .
Serious ?
It 's going to rain .
Tell me , Mr. Gray .
Must you always play the cynic ?
Hm ?
Look up .
- Actually , I 'd rather you didn 't ... - ( Shutter clicks )
Oblige me , Mr. Gray .
Have you been pursuing this delightful hobby for long ?
- No . It 's a gift from my father . - ( Thunder )
In return , he made me promise that I wouldn 't chain myself to more railings .
For suffrage , Mr. Gray .
Well , don 't you think that women should be given the vote ?
I don 't believe a woman should be given anything she can 't wear at night .
What a loss to the Front you are .
Think of all those Germans that you could bayonet with your epigrams .
I do apologize if I offend .
Oh , no , you 'll have to do rather better to offend me .
Then I humbly vow to redouble my efforts .
You know , I wonder if it 's true , what they say about you .
That beneath all the charm ,
you 're in fact quite heartless ?
They say I 'm charming ?
They say that you devote your whole life to pleasure .
Well , it 's clearly to be recommended .
If I look as good as you in 25 years , I shall be thoroughly happy .
I can assure you , pleasure is very different from happiness .
I mean , some things are more precious because they don 't last .
Mr. Gray ...
.. I believe I know your secret .
You do have a heart .
Those who go beneath the surface do so at their peril .
How terrifying .
I may let you chauffeur me again , Mr. Gray .
So , I 'll see you at Toynbee Hall tonight ?
Until then .
( Strident , lively tune )
Alice .
I 'd crawl the sewers before I 'd let my flesh and blood near him .
- Sit down , Grandad ! - What kind of unholiness
grants the face of a babe to such a man ?
Come along ! Come along , my dear !
MAN : Completely unnatural !
( Murmuring )
What ?
- Let him play ! - Quiet , please , ladies and gentlemen .
( Resumes tune )
( Playing becomes out of time )
You know , anyone would think you 're ashamed to be seen with me .
What happened in the hall ?
I don 't know what you mean .
You saw something .
You 're mistaken .
MAN : Well , I heard that he killed him .
MAN : We never ever again ...
EMILY : Mr. Gray !
It would be better if we were not seen together .
Better for whom ?
Tongues may wag against you .
I don 't care what they say .
You should .
The truth is ,
I 've done dreadful things .
My life ...
My life has been a monstrous corruption .
And there will be a price .
I won 't let anyone hurt you .
We should not meet again .
MAN : I told you it was him .
Step back .
I 'm coming for you , Dorian Gray .
WOMAN : You dirty bastard !
Dorian Gray , you bastard !
( Laughter )
You 're a disgrace !
Good evening , sir .
Mr. Harcourt here thinks there may be rats nesting in the attic .
- I haven 't the key . - Get out of my house .
But , Mr. Gray ...
And you .
( Rattles bars )
With respect , sir ...
.. I 've been with your family for two generations .
Your effects will follow .
( Rasping breath )
( Rats squeak )
( Rasping breaths )
( Guttural growl )
- Argh ! - ( Glass shatters )
( Sobs )
( Squelching )
( Low growl )
DORIAN : I want to be free .
I want to be ...
new ,
clean .
I want to be good .
Please .
Please , you have to help me .
If we repent ,
God is faithful and just .
Confess your mortal sins .
- Confess your mortal ... - This is not my true face !
If you could see my soul ...
Child , only God may see our souls .
I have seen my soul !
And I could show it to you .
It 's rotten .
It stinks .
It 's poison .
Help me .
( Gunshot )
You will die .
( Gurgling breaths )
I 'm sorry .
( Long , drawn-out gasp )
( Breathing stops )
Mr. Gray ?
Miss Wotton .
Please forgive my intrusion at this late hour .
You 're shaking .
- Look , come and sit by the fire . - I want to tell you ...
I want to tell you ... I want to tell you everything .
All right . Look at me .
Sh ! What is it ?
I need you ...
I need you to know ...
- what I am . - Sh !
It 's all right . Listen , sh ...
It 's all right .
Sh ...
Harry .
Morning .
Sleep well ?
Mr. Gray was in need of a friend .
Mmm .
Perhaps you could ask Mrs. Williams to prepare me some breakfast ?
Of course .
- ( Thunder ) - So young .
The world is hers .
- Harry , I ... - How dare you !
- She 's my daughter . - I 've changed .
You 've changed ?
But you don 't change , do you , Dorian ?
Why is that ?
Harry , you 're my oldest friend ...
You 're against nature . You stay away from her .
- I don 't want this to get ... - Stay away from her !
Mr. Gray !
I should apologize for my father .
Last night , you wanted to tell me something .
- Dorian ! - I want to begin again .
Far away from everything here .
I see . Well , I wouldn 't ...
Everything except you .
Dorian !
Yes .
DORIAN : Are you sure this is what you want ?
You 're what I want .
As I recall , Mr. Gray stored it in the attic .
He certainly wanted to protect it .
What secrets does he unlock ?
Nobody at all need know .
( Rasping breath )
Emily !
- What 's the meaning of this ? - I 'm sorry ...
Don 't come up here .
Please .
Never .
Give me the key , please , Emily .
- Well , what 's in there ? - Give me the key !
What 's in there ?
Please .
I beg you .
( Rasping groan )
( Growling )
( Chokes )
( Crunching )
DORIAN : It 's imperative it sails with us . To New York , yes .
I shall wrap it myself , but I 'd be grateful if you 'd send men to help carry it down .
Thank you .
The house should fetch a fine price , Mr. Gray .
Will you be leaving any of the furnishings ?
All of them .
You know , I think that he wants to make amends .
We owe him the benefit of the doubt .
I couldn 't let you go off to that ghastly continent without a farewell .
( Applause )
Come .
- I hear you sail at dawn ? - ( Laughs )
How romantic .
- Oh , to be young again . HENRY : Easily done .
Can you recall any errors you made in your early days ?
Very many , with much clarity .
HENRY : Then commit them over again .
To get back one 's youth , one merely has to repeat one 's follies .
- ( Laughs ) - Or you could barter your soul .
Darling , are you all right ?
Clumsy .
Sorry , excuse me , will you ?
( Car pulls up outside )
Sorry , darling , have you seen Harry ?
No . But look . Look what he dug out .
You never told me there was a painting of you .
Where is it ?
The war 's this way , mate !
Harry .
I want to see it .
See what ?
- Basil 's picture . - The picture was destroyed years ago .
I never liked it .
Show me .
It 's an old portrait of my grandfather .
Would you really kill me , Harry ?
You taught me that a man can rule his emotions .
But I can 't .
I can 't help loving your daughter more than I 've loved anything in my life .
And I can 't help how dear I still hold our friendship .
Please ...
Please don 't do this .
Just old trinkets , Harry . Why don 't we go back to the party ?
Basil ...
Harry ...
( Eerie breath )
( Gasps )
What are you ?
I am what you made me !
I lived the life that you preached but never dared practice .
I am everything that you were too afraid to be .
( Clatters )
But I was trying ...
I was trying so hard ...
.. to be a better man .
I 'm sorry .
Kelso was right .
You are ... You 're death .
Dorian ?
Dorian !
Harry , no !
( Growls )
- No ! - ( Gurgling scream )
Aaaargh !
( Screeching breaths )
No ! Come with me !
What are you doing ? Where 's Dorian ?
Dorian ?
- ( Rattles bars ) - Locked .
- Emily ! No , leave him ! - No ! No !
- No ! Dorian ... - ( Henry thuds to floor )
Give me the key .
Look , give me the key !
( Panting screams )
What 's in there ?
You have my whole heart , Emily .
Leave him !
My whole heart .
What ... ?
Emily , I beg you ...
No ...
Dorian !
No ! Dorian !
Aaaargh !
Raaargh !
Aaaaaargh !
I 'm still her father , Agatha .
And I 'm merely asking that you tell her ...
.. that I miss her
and that this will always be her home .
And maybe one day she 'll want to listen .
( Coughs )
Poor boy .
Who can bear to look at you now ?
( Door closes )
( Key turns in lock )